EMMANUEL TEYE NARTEY

Koforidua, Eastern Ghana| +233240699506 | aggrey.en@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Dedicated programmer and information technology enthusiast with experience in providing first-class web development solutions within any organizational setting, Application support services, Systems Administration and consistently exceeding expectations through a dedicated work ethic and passion for Information Technology.

SKILL

- Running background tasks and cron jobs.
- Responsive web development with modern technologies
- API development
- In-depth knowledge of hardware and software
- Ability to work well with people
- Strong oral and written communication skills
- Excellent organizational skills
- Ability to quickly establish working relationships with colleagues
- Effective reporting capabilities.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming with Python, Java, and JavaScript.
- Django and Django Rest Framework Web API Development.
- Nginx, Gunicorn
- Google Cloud Platform.
- Digital Ocean, Heroku, AWS, SendGrid, Twilio, Cloudinary
- Paystack, Thetella
- Unit Testing.
- Docker
- Celery, Celery Beat, Redis, RabbitMQ, Flower
- SQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB, Microsoft SQL
- · Debugging.

EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer December 2022 Current (part-time), Skuluu. – Accra, Greater Accra

- RESTful API development.
- Unit test and integration testing on the University project.
- Following modern technologies and architecture (GRPC API development and CQRS architecture)

Rock City Hotel November 2020 Current. – Kwahu Nkwatia, Eastern Ghana

IT Officer (BUSINESS APPLICATIONS AND SYSTEMS SUPPORT)

- System Administrator
- Leads the systems and IT support team
- Monitoring daily performance of servers
- Liaising with the various software vendors to resolve issues when the need be.
 Softcodes (sage 300), Vanhessen.be (Opera, Simphony, Materials control), Omega (Vertex)

Backend Developer September 2019 to October 2020 Xtayconnect Africa – Accra,

Greater Accra

- Responsible for the entire lifecycle, focusing on coding and debugging the e-commerce website.
- Unit and Integration testing of the system.
- Collaborate with a Front-end developer to integrate user-friendly elements with server-side logic.
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use.
- Follow emerging technology.

IT Support Assistant June 2019 to August 2020 National Service – National Disaster

Management Organization, Greater Accra Ada West Greater Accra

- Repairing of hardware systems.
- Assisting in the purchasing and installation of security cameras for clients.
- Identified and implemented prompt solutions to root causes of technical errors
- Router and network configuration.
- Network troubleshooting.

Junior Network Engineer May 2016 to November 2016 RANS Technology – Koforidua, E/R

- Installation, and configuration of new office telephones.
- Repairing of worn-out telephone cables in and outside the port.
- PC and Network Maintenance.
- Cisco Router and Switch configuration.

EXPERIENCE

- Management of Windows Active Directory, File Server, Application servers, Database Servers, etc.
- Developed a program for NADMO-ADA WEST SAGE covering various aspects of the department (Stock, HR, Operations, Accounts, etc.)
- Developed a program for the Ada West District Assembly Statistical Department used to track population data and market prices in the district
- Experience in running cron jobs, task schedulers, and asynchronous code with Django channels, celery, celery beat, etc. with a monitoring tool like flower with message brokers such as Redis, RabbitMQ, etc.
- Built a school management system app for students grading and exam report.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Higher National Diploma in Computer Network Management Koforidua Technical University – Koforidua	July 2019
Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)	August 2018
Network Training Academy Ghana- Koforidua Information Technology Essentials (Cisco)	May 2018
Network Training Academy Ghana- Koforidua	
WASSCE, General Arts	May 2014

Presbyterian Senior High School – Begoro, E/R

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Became a systems administrator team lead after less than a year of official employment.
- Gained in-depth knowledge of both project and team management in my current position.

Leader of the team that tested all the systems used by my current company. Sage 300, Opera, Simphony, Materials Control

- Team leads that assisted staff in getting acquainted with the company's new systems.
- Developed fully functional HR software used by my company.
- Transformed Anviz Time attendance clocking device database from access to SQL Server which made it easier for backups and a source of reliable data

CERTIFICATIONS

August 2018

• Cisco Certified Network Associates (CCNA)

July 2020

Ghana National Service Scheme

REFEREES

Mr. Daniel Owusu Ronald IT Assistant Manager Rock City Hotel Ghana Phone: (+233) 0244967848

Mr. Alfred Anan Operations Officer Ada West District Assembly National Disaster Management Organization (NADMO) Phone: (+233) 0241-601-221

Mr. Emmanuel Kwaku Owusu Larbi Chief Executive Officer XtayConnect Africa Phone: (+233) 024-478-3244 / (+233) 024-636-0674

WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

https://www.linkedin.com/in/emmanuel-aggrev-133233137

https://github.com/Emmanuel-Aggrey